{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The area of the concrete in compression plus the area of reinforcement transferred on the basis of modular ratio, is called", "opta": "transferred section", "optb": "equivalent section", "optc": "cracked section", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If D is the overall thickness of the slab, the diameter of the reinforcing bars should not exceed", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "E", "explanation": "The diameter of reinforcing bars shall not exceed one eighth of the total thickness of the slab."}, {"question": "The gap between web plates and flange plates for fillet welds should not be more than", "opta": "0.5 mm", "optb": "0.75 mm", "optc": "1.0 mm", "optd": "1.25 mm", "opte": "1.5 mm", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A continuous beam shall be deemed to be a deep beam if the ratio of its effective span to overall depth, is", "opta": "2.0", "optb": "2.5", "optc": "less than 2", "optd": "less than 2.5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The depth 'd' of webs without horizontal stiffeners and consisting of tongue plates is taken lesser than the depth of the girder between the flanges less the sum of the depth of the tongue plates, and", "opta": "eight times the sum of the thickness of tongue plates", "optb": "six times the sum of the thickness of tongue plates", "optc": "four times the sum of the thickness of tongue plates", "optd": "None of the above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For design of a column the eccentricity of loading shall be taken as the distance from the assumed point of application of the load to the centroid of the column, subject to a minimum of", "opta": "10 mm", "optb": "20 mm", "optc": "30 mm", "optd": "40 mm", "opte": "50 mm", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If l is the effective span in metres and D is overall depth of the section in mm, the structure may be accepted after 24 hour load test, provided the maximum deflection in mm is less than", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The approximate value of torsion constant k for a box of depth d, width b, and having uniform thickness t, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the formula a + bk for the calculation of the net effective section of single angles in tension connected by one leg only, the value of k, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The concrete is deemed not to comply with the strength requirements if the strength is less than the greater of", "opta": "characteristic strength minus 1.35 times the standard deviation", "optb": "0.8 times the characteristic strength", "optc": "the average strength of all the samples is less than the characteristic strength plus  times the standard deviation.", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum area of compression reinforcement in a beam of cross section B x D is limited to", "opta": "0.02 BD", "optb": "0.03 BD", "optc": "0.04 BD", "optd": "0.05 BD", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Moist curing of the exposed surfaces of concrete is done at least for", "opta": "3 days", "optb": "5 days", "optc": "7 days", "optd": "14 days", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following:", "opta": "The gross section of the web of rolled I-beams is the depth of the beam multiplied by the web thickness", "optb": "The gross section of the web of channels is the depth of the web multiplied by its thickness", "optc": "The gross section of the web of plate girders is the depth of the web plate multiplied by its thinkness", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the ratio of effective span to overall depth of a simply supported beam is equal or greater than 1 but less than or equal to 2, the lever arm, is", "opta": "0.2 (l + 2D)", "optb": "0.3 (l + 3D)", "optc": "0.2 (l + 3D)", "optd": "0.3 (l + 2D)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the slenderness ratio of a column is more than 160, the compressive stress obtained by the secant formula is multiplied by a factor in which value of x is", "opta": "0.9", "optb": "1.1", "optc": "1.2", "optd": "1.5", "opte": "None of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For battened struts, the effective length is increased by", "opta": "5%", "optb": "7.5%", "optc": "10%", "optd": "12.5%", "opte": "15%", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum horizontal deflection of a column of actual length L, when subjected to lateral forces, may be upto", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The test strength of the sample is taken as the average of the strength of", "opta": "2 specimens", "optb": "3 specimens", "optc": "4 specimens", "optd": "5 specimens", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum deflection of a structure should not normally exceed lesser of the span/350 or", "opta": "10 mm", "optb": "15 mm", "optc": "20 mm", "optd": "25 mm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement regarding columns.", "opta": "The cross sectional area of longitudinal reinforcement, should not be less than 0.8% nor more than 4% of its gross sectional area", "optb": "The minimum of longitudinal bars provided in rectangular and circular columns are 4 and 6 respectively", "optc": "In helically reinforced column, the minimum number of longitudinal reinforcement should be six", "optd": "If the effective length of a column is less than three times its lateral dimension, it is generally called a pedestal", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For heavily reinforced concrete member, the nominal maximum size of the aggregates should be restricted to", "opta": "5 mm less than the minimum clear distance between the main bars", "optb": "5 mm less than the minimum cover to the reinforcement", "optc": "smaller of (a) and (b)", "optd": "greater of (a) and (b)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The minimum pitch i.e.,  the distance between centres of rivet holes is not less than", "opta": "1.5 times the hole diameter", "optb": "2.0 times the hole diameter", "optc": "2.5 times the hole diameter", "optd": "3.0 times the hole diameter", "opte": "None of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dispersion of load through the flange to web is considered as dispersed uniformly at an angle \u03b8\u00b0 is", "opta": "10\u00b0", "optb": "15\u00b0", "optc": "20\u00b0", "optd": "25\u00b0", "opte": "30\u00b0", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The grade of concrete generally not used in the reinforced concrete, is", "opta": "M 10", "optb": "M 15", "optc": "M 20", "optd": "M 40", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The outstand of stiffeners should be (where t is the thickness of flat).", "opta": "6 t", "optb": "8 t", "optc": "10 t", "optd": "12 t", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the plain reinforcing bars in compression, the permissible design bond stress in tension, is increased by", "opta": "10%", "optb": "15%", "optc": "20%", "optd": "25%", "opte": "30%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cover to the main reinforced may be reduced up to one third of the specified cover but not less than", "opta": "5 mm", "optb": "7 mm", "optc": "10 mm", "optd": "15 mm", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum compressive strength on 15 cm cubes of M 20 grade concrete at 7 days, should be a minimum of", "opta": "7 N/mm2", "optb": "10 N/mm2", "optc": "15 N/mm2", "optd": "20 N/mm2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reduced level of third floor of a building near a column is 205.350 m. The reduced levels of the undersides of four beams supporting the fourth floor framing into the column mutually perpendicular are 208.350 m, 208.450 m, 208.500 m and 208.550 m. The supported length of the column is", "opta": "3.000 m", "optb": "3.100 m", "optc": "3.150 m", "optd": "3.200 m", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The distance between, rivet line and the nearest edge of a joint not exposed to weather, is taken (where t is thickness in mm of the thinner outside plate).", "opta": "6 t", "optb": "8 t", "optc": "10 t", "optd": "12 t", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct precaution while spilicing the reinforcing bars", "opta": "These are provided away from the sections of maximum stress", "optb": "These are staggered", "optc": "These are provided if the B.M. is more than 50% of M.R.", "optd": "Not more than half the bars are spliced at a section", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If \u0394 is the deviation of the individual test strength from the average of n samples, the standard deviation of concrete of the given grade is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The over all depth of a solid slab is 20 cm and effective depth is 15 cm. The horizontal distance between parallel main reinforcement should not be more than", "opta": "30 cm", "optb": "40 cm", "optc": "45 cm", "optd": "60 cm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ratio of minimum compressive strength on 15 cm cubes prepared with the concrete of M 20 grade and M 40 grade, at 7 days should be at least", "opta": "1/3", "optb": "1/2", "optc": "3/2", "optd": "2.0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The minimum compressive strength on 15 cm cubes of M 30 grade concrete at 7 days, should be a minimum of", "opta": "7 N/mm2", "optb": "10 N/mm2", "optc": "20 N/mm2", "optd": "30 N/mm2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The grade of plain concrete to be used in sea water or structures exposed to sea water, should be", "opta": "M lO", "optb": "M 15", "optc": "M 20", "optd": "M 30", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In case of continuous beams, the distance between the points of zero moment, may be obtained as (where l is the effective span).", "opta": "0.5 l", "optb": "0.6 l", "optc": "0.7 l", "optd": "0.8 l", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reinforcing bars in beams are not bundled in contact if the diameter of the bars, exceeds", "opta": "12 mm", "optb": "20 mm", "optc": "35 mm", "optd": "30 mm", "opte": "36 mm", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the reinforced concrete member totally immersed in sea water, the normal cover provided for the reinforcing bars is further increased by", "opta": "10 mm", "optb": "20 mm", "optc": "30 mm", "optd": "40 mm", "opte": "50 mm", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The effective and actual lengths of a cantilever are same if continuous at the support,", "opta": "unstrained against torsion at the support and free at the end", "optb": "with partial restraint against torsion of the support and free at the end", "optc": "restrained against torsion at the support and free at the end", "optd": "none of the these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The value of fbct in the formula  for calculating the thickness of a Rectangular base, according to IS : 800-1982, is", "opta": "1500 kg/cm2", "optb": "1650 kg/cm2", "optc": "1800kg/cm2", "optd": "1890 kg/cm2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The slenderness ratio of single angle discontinuous struts conmected by a single rivet or bolt, shall not exceed", "opta": "110", "optb": "130", "optc": "150", "optd": "180", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In adverse circumtances, the reinforced concrete member immersed in sea water or subjected to sea spray, the maximum permissible cover for the reinforcing bars, should not exceed", "opta": "40 mm", "optb": "50 mm", "optc": "60 mm", "optd": "70 mm", "opte": "75 mm", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a column is subjected to dead load and super imposed load only, the maximum ratio  should not be greater than", "opta": "180", "optb": "250", "optc": "350", "optd": "400", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the dimensions of a rectangular section of a short column are 15 cm x 20 cm, its unsupported length should be restricted to", "opta": "9.0 m", "optb": "10.0 m", "optc": "11.0 m", "optd": "12.0 m", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The designed transverse shear in lacing is assumed as", "opta": "2.5% of axial load", "optb": "3% of axial load", "optc": "3.5% of axial load", "optd": "4% of axial load.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the stability of a structural part, the weight or anchorage should be", "opta": "1.2 times the minimum overturning moment due to dead load", "optb": "1.4 times the minimum overturning moment due to dead load", "optc": "sum of (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The creep coefficient i.e. the ratio of ultimate creep and elastic strain after", "opta": "7 days is 2.2", "optb": "28 days is 1.6", "optc": "365 days is 1.1", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For rolled I-beams and channels, permissible tensile and compressive stresses does not exceed", "opta": "1400 kg/cm2", "optb": "1500 kg/cm2", "optc": "1650 kg/cm2", "optd": "1800 kg/cm2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In compression members, the lap length of a bar should not be less than", "opta": "12 \u03c6", "optb": "16 \u03c6", "optc": "20 \u03c6", "optd": "24 \u03c6", "opte": "30 \u03c6", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}